A Guide to the Office of the Vice-President, Louis A. Pardue Records, 1950-1963
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Office of the Vice-President, Louis A. Pardue Records, 1950-1963
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Pardue, Louis A., 1901-1963
RG 3/3
33.6 Cubic Feet 24 boxes
Collection contains 1,072 folders consisting of general correspondence, general reports, financial reports, enrollment statistics, commencement and inaugural reports, minutes, and departmental information collected by Dr. Louis A. Pardue from 1950 through 1963 while holding the offices of Vice-President and Director of Graduate Studies. There is also correspondence relating to the Oak Ridge Institute of Nuclear Science (ORINS)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Pardue Papers were transferred to the University Archives from the University's Records Management Services September 11, 1973 and June 30, 1978.
Biographical Note
Dr. Louis A. Pardue (1901-1963), a native of Scottsville, Kentucky, received his Bachelor's and Master's degrees from the University of Kentucky and a Ph.D. in Physics from Yale University. He also taught physics at Yale University, Lehigh University, and Lincoln Memorial University. During World War II, he served both at Chicago and Oak Ridge, Tennessee, in the "Manhattan Project," which developed the atomic bomb, and along with 17 other scientists in the "Manhattan Project," signed a petition to the President of United States urging limited and responsible use of atomic weapons. He came to the Virginia Polytechnic Institute in 1950 from the University of Kentucky, where he was Dean of the Graduate School. While at VPI, Dr. Pardue, held the offices of Vice-President and Director of Graduate Studies for roughly 13 years and is credited with playing a major role in the development of instructional and research programs at VPI. Dr. Pardue died on April 27, 1963.
Scope and Content
This collection consists primarily of correspondence relating to Pardue's duties both as Vice-President and Director of Graduate Studies. However, there also are extensive correspondence and other material of the Oak Ridge Institute of Nuclear Science (ORINS). VPI was a member of ORINS and Pardue served on the Council and Board of Directors.
Also included in the collection are: Education Policy and Program Committee minutes (1950-51); correspondence with the General Education Board and the State Board of Education; correspondence, proposals, and committee minutes concerning establishment of joint Home Economics program for VPI and Radford; annual reports (1949-51); Southern Association of Colleges and Universities material; minutes and other items from the Board of Control for Southern Regional Education; correspondence from the Department of Health Education and Welfare; correspondence with President Newman and President Hahn; reports from the Engineering Faculty concerning military situation at VPI; notices, memoranda, and reports from the Federal Communications Commission Joint Committee on Educational Television; Graduate Committee minutes (1949-55); a list of advanced degrees given from 1889-1950; memoranda, general rules, articles and other items dealing with the Corps of Cadets and ROTC; correspondence, minutes, and other items concerning the National Collegiate Athletic Association; news releases; speech material; questionnaires on various subjects; State Board of Education material; Student Activities Committee material including charters and other items of various student organizations; correspondence and reports dealing with the VPI Educational Foundation; minutes and other material from conferences of Deans of Graduate Schools (1948-54); Southern Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools Committee material; Centennial Committee material; scattered Academic Council minutes and course proposals; Association of Land-Grant Colleges information; material concerning faculty listings, salaries, appointments, resignations, leaves of absence, and adjustments (1951 to 1962); correspondence with the agriculture, applied mechanics, applied science and business administration, architecture, biology, chemistry, engineering, English and foreign language, geology, mathematics, physics, physical education, philosophy and religion, vocational education, and veterinary medicine departments at VPI; letters to the United States Congress; information from the Atomic Energy Commission; material relating to the Fulbright program; correspondence from students and their families; correspondence to administrative departments and faculty; National Defense Education Act (NDEA) reports; scholarship, graduate assistantship, and doctoral fellowship information; correspondence from the Danville branch of VPI; National Science Foundation materials; nuclear energy information; Ford Foundation material; reports from the Association of University Professors; material used in summer programs at VPI for high school teachers; student information concerning commencement, foreign students, letters of recommendation, international exchange programs, and student censure; Science Advisory Committee reports and correspondence.
The ORINS material includes correspondence, annual reports, Board of Directors minutes, budget reports, project reports and proposals, organizational charts, news releases, and Glenwood School drawings (architectural layouts for proposed addition to ORINS).
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically in alphabetical sequence. For all years, there may be some material dated prior to that particular year.
Index Terms
Persons:
Pardue, Louis A., 1901-1963
Subjects:
Science and Technology; University Archives; University History; Virginia Polytechnic Institute
Contents List
- A, General, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  correspondence and reports concerning religion and education, accreditation, and acceleration of graduating engineering students
- Admissions Office-Farrier, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  admittance information and correspondence with ROTC and Architecture departments
- Agriculture-Young, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  consideration of expansion of curriculum and activities of Agricultural Extension Division
- Applied Mechanics-Pletta, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  salary survey of Virginia engineering schools
- Applied Science and Business Administration-Johnson, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  proposal from the dean about adding more humanities courses
- Architecture-Cowgill, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  possibility of losing department's accreditation
- Association of American Colleges and Universities, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  lack of VPI membership in A.A.C.U.
- Association of Land-Grant Colleges and State Universities, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  committee reports, budgetary information, and correspondence about graduate programs
- Biology-Wilson, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  report on first Pan-American Veterinary Congress held in Peru
- Board of Control for Southern Regional Education (4 folders), 1951 (Box 1, Folder 10a-d)
  committee reports, meeting agendas, and procedural guidelines
- Business Manager-Cassell, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  summary of budget requests and capital outlays as well as a budgetary report for the Engineering Experiment Station
- C, General, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  contains letters from Central Scientific Co., a consultant firm, and Coe College
- Chemical Engineering-Vilbrandt, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  survey of departments in North Carolina, Maryland and Virginia; report on graduate programs
- Chemistry-Watson, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  research proposals, report on the Reducing action of metals in ammonia
- Civil Engineering-Brinker, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Federal grant application
- Cooperative Program of Graduate Work in Education, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  standardization of the Teacher Education graduate program
- D, General, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  list of the floor space used by the various departments
- Deans-Agriculture, Applied Science, Engineering, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  correspondence and faculty funding program information
- Disciplinary Committee, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  regulations concerning student honor code offenders
- E, General, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  enrollment information and correspondence concerning college programs affiliated with the Boy Scouts of America
- Educational Policy and Program Committee, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  meeting minutes
- Engineering-Norris, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  correspondence about graduate and undergraduate programs as
- English and Foreign Language-Harrison, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  grade percentage statistics from English and Foreign language classes
- Extension Service-Dietrick, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- F, General, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  fellowship program, correspondence about school work load for VPI freshmen
- Faculty Appointments, Agriculture, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Faculty Appointments, Applied Science and Business Administration, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Faculty Appointments, Engineering (2 folders), 1951 (Box 1, Folder 28a-b)
- Faculty, Leaves of Absence, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Faculty, Pending Adjustments, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  information about faculty promotions
- Faculty, Resignations, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- G, General, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  correspondence from the General Institute of Technology and a general survey concerning religious attitudes of college students
- General Education Board, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  correspondence regarding VPI exchanges with the GEB of New York City about scholarships and grants
- Geology-Cooper, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  proposal about establishing a geology camp at Saltville, Virginia
- Guidance and Placement-Cato, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  correspondence concerning the Selective Service Qualification test at VPI
- H, General correspondence from the Huston Alumni Chapter, F. Helsaback, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  correspondence from the Huston Alumni Chapter, F. Helsaback, and M. Huntley
- Higher Education, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  statements about military draft deferments for college students, and a copy of higher education financial aid bill presented in the Senate
- Home Economics-Tate, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  student and staff complaints concerning Home Economics department's administration
- Home Economics Committee, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  correspondence and proposals concerning the establishment of a joint program between VPI and Radford, minutes of committee set up to oversee this program
- Institute of International Education, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  Fulbright division
- Invitations, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  accepted and rejected
- K, General, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  study of remedial reading programs
- Library-Robb, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  debate over binding student theses
- Mathematics-Hatcher, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  grade percentages and correspondence encouraging professors to teach fewer classes and conduct more research
- Military-Merritt, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  instructions for behavior of corps of cadets and guidelines for compulsory two year participation in corps for students
- Minutes of Graduate Committee, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- National Education Association, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  reports and confidential memos concerning a perceived shortage of military personnel
- Personnel Office-Richmond, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  includes survey from American Association of University Professors concerning salary increases for teaching faculty
- Plant Pathology and Physiology-Wingard, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  complaints about shortage of laboratory equipment
- President-Walter Newman, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  Newman's involvement in a South Carolina lawsuit about racial segregation in education for more information about this lawsuit, see: files #1 and #65 in box 6 of Newman's papers
- Public Health Service, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  correspondence concerning financial assistance for employees attending VPI
- Public Relations-McNeil, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  reclassification of students' class standing (Freshmen, Sophomore,etc..); reports about history and by-laws of cadet corps
- R, General, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  correspondence regarding instruction in radio and television technology
- Registrar-Slusher, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  "survey of small classes" survey
- Southern Association of Colleges and Universities, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  annual reports, monthly bulletins, and circulars
- State Board of Education, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  annual reports and "outlines for suggested courses in government and history at Virginia's secondary schools"
- Statistics-Harshbarger, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  U.S. Naval funding for research
- Student and Students' Families Correspondence, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  re-admittance of former students and disciplinary actions against students
- Student Affairs and Foreign Students, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  correspondence and reports concerning students called up by draft board and regulations on student-owned vehicles
- T, General, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  proposal for introduction of business administration courses at the Danville branch
- Veterinary Medicine Selection Committee, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  placement of VPI students in the veterinary program at University of Georgia
- VPI Educational Foundation-Hutcheson, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  annual report to the board of directors
- Vocational Education-Sanders, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  reports from "34th Annual Conference of White Instructors of Vocational Agriculture"
- W, General, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  agricultural engineering newsletter
- A, General, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  circulars, bulletins, inquiries, and announcements
- Admissions Office-Farrier, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  statement on "Basic Division of VPI"
- Agronomy-Dunton, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  pasture and forage crop research
- Applied Mechanics-Pletta, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  Petition to Southern Regional Education Board for "establishment of a Regional Center in Applied Mechanics at VPI"
- Architecture-Cowgill, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  proposed expansion of facilities and cooperative office supply purchase program
- Association of Land-Grant Colleges and Universities, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  agenda for and correspondence about 66th annual meeting
- Board of Control for the Southern Regional Education Association (2 folders), 1952 (Box 2, Folder 71a-b)
  VPI had no representative on Board of Directors, but received meeting minutes and newsletters
- Business Manager-Cassell, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  budget summary for vice-president's office
- Ceramic Engineering-Dear, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  minutes from Lithographer's meeting
- Chemical Engineering-Vilbrandt, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  report from engineering faculty regarding discontent and high levels of resignation of cadet corps members
- Chemistry-Watson, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  research proposals and departmental policy on "outside contract work"
- Commission on Graduate Programs, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  agenda and reports from meetings
- Conference of Deans of Southern Graduate Schools, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  meeting agenda and reports
- Engineering-Norris, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  financial summary for Danville branch and redesign of merit salary increase programs
- Faculty Adjustments (2 folders), 1952 (Box 2, Folder 79a-b)
- Faculty Appointments, Agriculture, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 80)
- Faculty Appointments, Applied Science and Business Administration, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 81)
- Faculty Appointments, Engineering, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 82)
- Faculty, Leaves of Absence, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 83)
- Faculty, Library, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 84)
- Faculty, Resignations, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 85)
- Faculty, Summer sessions, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 86)
- General Education Board, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 87)
- Graduate School (2 folders), 1952 (Box 3, Folder 88a-b)
- Guidance and Placement-Cato, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 89)
- Guidance Programs in Virginia, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 90)
- Home Economic Committee-VPI and Radford (2 folders), 1952 (Box 3, Folder 91-92)
- L, General, 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 93)
- Military-Merritt, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 94)
- Mimeographs, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 95)
- National Research Council, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 96)
- Physical Education-Younger, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 97)
- President-Newman, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 98)
- Questionnaires, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 99)
- Registrar-Slusher, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 100)
- Southern Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 101)
- Southern Regional Education Board, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 102)
- Student Activities Committee, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 103)
- Television (2 folders), 1952 (Box 3, Folder 104a-b)
- University of North Carolina, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 105)
- Veterinary Medicine, Selection Committee, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 106)
- A, General, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 107)
- Admissions Office, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 108)
- Association of Land-Grant Colleges and Universities (2 folders), 1953 (Box 3, Folder 109a-b)
- Biology-Wilson, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 110)
- Chemical Engineering-Vilbrandt, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 111)
- Civil and Sanitary Engineering-Brinker, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 112)
- Conference of Deans of Southern Graduate Schools (3 folders), 1953 (Box 4, Folder 113a-c)
- Deans, General, 1952-1953 (Box 4, Folder 114)
- Dean of Agriculture-Dietrick, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 115)
- Dean of Applied Science and Business Administration-Johnston, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 116)
- Dean of Engineering and Architecture-Whittemore, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 117)
- Education Policy and Program Committee, 1952-1953 (Box 4, Folder 118)
- Electrical Engineering-Murray, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 119)
- Extension Training, Cooperative Industry, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 120)
- Faculty, Absences, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 121)
- Faculty, Adjustments, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 122)
- Faculty, Appointments, Agriculture, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 123)
- Faculty, Appointments, Applied Science and Business Administration, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 124)
- Faculty, Appointments, Engineering and Architecture, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 125)
- Faculty, Library, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 126)
- Faculty, Resignations, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 127)
- Faculty, Summer Session, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 128)
- FCC, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 129)
- General Education Board, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 130)
- Geology-Cooper, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 131)
- Guidance and Placement-Cato, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 132)
- H, General, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 133)
- Industrial Engineering-Manning, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 134)
- Institute of International Education, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 135)
- Invitations, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 136)
- Memorandum, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 137)
- Military-Devine, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 138)
- Mimeographs, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 139)
- N, General, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 140)
- National Collegiate Athletic Association, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 141)
- News Releases and Speech Material, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 142)
- President-Newman, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 143)
- Questionnaires, General, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 144)
- Questionnaires, Southern Regional Education Board, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 145)
- Radford College-Martin, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 146)
- Registrar-Slusher, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 147)
- Southern Regional Education Board, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 148)
- 1953 Southern Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools (2 folders), 1953 (Box 5, Folder 149a-b)
- State Board of Education for Virginia, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 150)
- Statistics-Harshbarger, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 151)
- Student Activities-Guthridge, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 152)
- Television, Roanoke and Blacksburg, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 153)
- VPI Educational Foundation-Hutcheson, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 154)
- Vocational Education, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 155)
- A, General, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 156)
- Admissions Office-Farrier, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 157)
- Agricultural Experiment Station, 1952-1954 (Box 5, Folder 158)
- Assistantship Recommendations, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 159)
- Association of Land-Grant Colleges and Universities, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 160)
- Chemical Engineering-Vilbrandt, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 161)
- Chemistry-Watson, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 162)
- Civil Engineering-Brinker, 1949-1954 (Box 5, Folder 163)
- Doctoral Programs Offered by Southern Universities, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 164)
- Engineering and Architecture-Whittemore, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 165)
- Engineering Experiment Station-Whittemore, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 166)
- F, General, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 167)
- Faculty, Adjustments, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 168)
- Faculty, Appointments, Agriculture, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 169)
- Faculty, Appointments, Applied Science and Business Administration, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 170)
- Faculty, Appointments, Engineering and Architecture, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 171)
- Faculty, Library and General, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 172)
- Faculty, Personnel Listing, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 173)
- Faculty, Resignations, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 174)
- Faculty, Tenure, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 175)
- Graduate School, General, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 176)
- H, General, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 177)
- I, General, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 178)
- Institute of International Education, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 179)
- Invitations, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 180)
- M, General, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 181)
- Military-Devine, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 182)
- N, General, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 183)
- National Science Foundation, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 184)
- Physics-Robeson, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 185)
- President-Newman, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 186)
- Questionnaires, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 187)
- Quotations, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 188)
- Registrar-Slusher, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 189)
- Salary for VPI Personnel (2 folders), 1954 (Box 6, Folder 190a-b)
- Southern Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools (6 folders), 1954 (Box 6, Folder 191a-f)
- Southern Regional Education Board (2 folders), 1954 (Box 6, Folder 192a-b)
- American Council on Education, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 193)
- Animal Husbandry-Litton, 1954-1955 (Box 6, Folder 194)
- Association of Land-Grant Colleges (3 folder), 1955 (Box 6, Folder 195a-c)
- B, General, 1954-1955 (Box 6, Folder 196)
- Basic Division, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 197)
- Biology, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 198)
- Conference of Deans of Southern Graduate Schools, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 199)
- Deans, General, 1954-1955 (Box 6, Folder 200)
- Engineering and Architecture-Whittemore, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 201)
- Engineering Experiment Station, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 202)
- Faculty Adjustments, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 203)
- Faculty Appointments, Agriculture, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 204)
- Faculty Appointments, Applied Science and Business Administration, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 205)
- Faculty Appointments, Engineering and Architecture, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 206)
- Faculty Resignations, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 207)
- Grade Percentages, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 208)
- Graduate Assistants, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 209)
- Graduate Assistants Applications, 1954-1955 (Box 7, Folder 210)
- Graduate Scholarship Announcements, 1953-1955 (Box 7, Folder 211)
- Graduate School, General, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 212)
- Graphics-Castleman, 1952-1955 (Box 7, Folder 213)
- Guidance and Placement-Cato, 1954-1955 (Box 7, Folder 214)
- Higher Education in Virginia, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 215)
- IBM, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 216)
- Industrial Engineering-Manning, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 217)
- Institute of International Education (2 folder), 1955 (Box 7, Folder 218a-b)
- J, General, 1954-1955 (Box 7, Folder 219)
- M, General, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 220)
- Memo Notices Regarding the Military, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 221)
- Military, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 222)
- Mimeograph, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 223)
- Mining Engineering-Holland, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 224)
- Minutes of Graduate Committee Meetings, 1952-1955 (Box 7, Folder 225)
- National Research Council, 1953-1955 (Box 7, Folder 226)
- National Science Foundation, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 227)
- Physics-Hahn, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 228)